Contact

410-491-3879 (Mobile) megaabyte@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jill-bates-rn-msn-874b2b29 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Clinical

Health Education

Educational Technology

Languages

Spanish (Limited Working)

French (Professional Working)

Jill Bates, RN MSN

Travel Nurse at Allianz

Falls Church, Virginia

Summary

I have an MSN majoring in Nursing Education. I have 16 plus years and counting in critical care nursing including ICU, Trauma, IR, and Cardiac Cath Lab and have gained valuable experience with hemodynamics, medical devices, critical thinking, and scrubbing for procedures. I have a passion for patient care and expanding my nursing knowledge as well as imparting my skills with others. I am a very technical person who is detail oriented and loves the how and why. I would like to enter into medical industry as a clinical expert/consultant and also attain my CNOR; I am also considering CRNFA programs.

Experience

Allianz

Travel Nurse

April 2020 - Present (3 months)

Bethesda, Maryland, United States

OR/Critical Care

Inova Health System

Nurse

September 2016 - May 2020 (3 years 9 months)

Fairfax, Virginia

Operating Room RN Level I Trauma, Charge/Circ/Scrub

Chesapeake Medical Staffing and Home Care

Registered Nurse

April 2005 - April 2020 (15 years 1 month)

Timonium, Maryland

Served as a RN within the various hospitals in the Baltimore Metro area, Baltimore County, Harford County, Howard County, Prince Georges County, and Gettysburg, Pennsylvania. Units hired/contracted for: OR, ICU, Cardiac Cath Lab, ER, IMC, Telemetry, Medical-Surgical. Also acted as preceptor and educator in IR, ICU and Cath lab pertaining to plan of care, skills, MAC lab,

and procedures. Currently work on a per-diem basis and occasional contract basis

WellSpan Health

RN

December 2014 - October 2015 (11 months)

York, Pennsylvania

RN II GOR at level 1 Trauma Center, Circulated/ Scrub

LifeBridge Health

4 years 8 months

RN II- General Operating Room January 2013 - January 2015 (2 years 1 month)

Baltimore, Maryland Area

Circulating and sometimes scrub nurse in the General Operating Room, maintains patient safety in collaboration with the multi-disciplinary OR team. Cases range from general, gynecological, DaVinci, neuro, neuro-spine, bariatric, ENT, orthopaedic, and trauma.

RN MSN, RN II

June 2010 - January 2013 (2 years 8 months)

ICU 4 South

Multi-specialty intensive care unit in a level II trauma center. Primary focus is on hemodynamically unstable patients, traumatic head injury, including neurogenic, cardiogenic, septic, and hemovolemic shock, as well as major post surgical and medical acute care patients. Focused in a evidenced-based research environment, hospital has Magnet Status accredidation. Act as preceptor, charge, resource as well as strong nursing critical thinking and skill presence at the bedside.

Johns Hopkins Bayview Medical Center Nurse Clinician, Interventional radiology April 2008 - June 2009 (1 year 3 months)

Dynamic IR nurse clinician responsible for advocating and sedating patients and care before, during, and after procedures. Scubbed for procedures within adult patient populations. Precepted nurses new to the IR environment. Ensured hemodynamic stability for critically ill patients.

University of Maryland Full partner April 2003 - January 2008 (4 years 10 months)

Page 2 of 4

University of Maryland Medical Center, Interventional Radiology and CCL

Served as a educational resource, charge nurse, precepted and performed as a critical care Imaging nurse within the Scope of Practice under the Maryland Board of Nursing and guidelines of the American Imaging Nurses Association. Administered cancious sedation for adult in/out patients, including neuro-interventional radiology. Scrubbed primarily in many IR cases including uterine fibroid embolization, TIPPS, perm cath placement, vascular angiography, fistula declot, and many more. Was circulating nurse in the Cardiac Cath lab, responsible for patient care and hemodynamic montoring and acute MI. Also monitored cases with MAC lab system.

The Medicines Company
Clinical Consultant
September 2003 - May 2004 (9 months)
Parsippany, New Jersey

Acted as clinical consultant as a support for sales representative for the drug Angiomax (bivalirudin); accompanied sales rep within given territory and presented in services to cardiac Cath lab staff at various hospitals in the DELMARVA region. Also received specific clinical education for presenting the drug via seminar.

The Endoscopy Center
Charge Nurse, Assistant Nurse Manager
June 2002 - April 2003 (11 months)
Towson, Maryland

Circulating RN in various endoscopy procedures, charge nurse and assistant nurse manager. Precepted nurses new to the endoscopy environment, ensured consistent education of staff. Maintained credentialing and certification of all nursing staff and capable on thriving in a fast, high-paced environment.

The Johns Hopkins Hospital
Clinical Nurse Intern/Nurse Clinician I CSICU
June 1999 - June 2002 (3 years 1 month)
Baltimore, Maryland Area

Began nursing career as a CNI while attending nursing school at Johns Hopkins School of Nursing. Transitioned into a RN post graduation. Attained skills to maintain stability for post-surgical cardiac patients who underwent CABG, LVAD/BIVAD, IABP, Heart Mate, CVVHD, ECCMO, PFO closure, valve

replacement, heart/lung transplant, and pace make management. Also gained skills with various IV agents, monitoring and documentation.

Education

Walden University

Master of Science - MS, Nurse practitioner · (2020 - 2021)

Walden University

DNP · (2017 - 2021)

Walden University

MSN, Education · (2008 - 2011)

The Johns Hopkins University

BSN, Nursing · (1998 - 2000)

AHS

Diploma, College Prep · (1981 - 1985)